this problem gives us
a local variable name referencing the
string roger
and we've been asked to compare name
with
a different string roger that has
letters of a different case
we've been asked to ignore the case of
both strings
in this comparison ignoring the case
we want to print true if the values are
the same
and false if they are not
so recall that when we perform equality
comparison
on strings
strings that contain the same letters
but of a different case will not be seen
as
equal so on line two we're outputting
the
return value of comparing name
to the string roger with letters of a
different case
and running our code you can see that
this returns false
this problem instructs us to compare
these two strings
while ignoring the case of both strings
in this case we want a comparison of
these two strings to return
true in ruby we can compare the value of
two strings
while ignoring the case using the
kcmp method
so we'll invoke this method on the name
local variable
and pass in roger as an argument
to this method
running our code again you can see that
the output is zero
and this may seem confusing
this method doesn't return a boolean
instead it returns an integer
if both strings are equal 0 will be
returned
if the calling string is seen as
greater than the string passed in as an
argument
our method would return 1 and if the
calling string
is evaluated as less than the argument
the method will return negative one
so our method invocation on line two
returned
zero indicating that the value of these
two strings
is the same however our problem
description tells us that we need to
output either true or
false since we know that this method
invocation returns zero
when the values are equal we can compare
the return value of this method
to zero this comparison will return a
boolean either true
or false which will be output by our
call to put us
so let's run our code now and we're
expecting to output true
[Music]
and that's the behavior we see
the second step to this problem is to
compare the
name variable to the string dave
now in this case we are expecting to
output
false these two strings are not
equal regardless of case
again in this case we can simply compare
the return value
of this method invocation
to zero we know that the case cmp method
will only return zero if the values of
the two strings
are the same so we know that comparing
that return value to
0 will always return false when the
strings are not equal
let's run our code
and we see the expected output
for more information on this method and
how it works
be sure to look at the ruby
documentation
you